MUHAMMAD DANIAL GAUHAR

Flat H-9, Park View Apartment, Block 10, Gulshan-e-Iqbal, Karachi · +92 333 0376076 muhammaddanialgauhar@gmail.com · www.linkedin.com/in/danialgauhar/

Strong analytical thinker with problem solving and communication skills. Interested in the position of Data Scientist to utilize data science experience. Bringing hands-on experience in using advanced statistical techniques and solid programming skills.

EXPERIENCE

June, 2022 - Current

DATA SCIENCE TRAINER, INSTITUTE OF COST AND MANAGEMENT ACCOUNTANTS OF PAKISTAN (ICMA PAKISTAN)

My Provide training on real world data using Data Science and Machine Learning tools. Provide consultancy and training on implementation of Data Science and Artificial Intelligence at different level of a company. Provide guidance on startup related to Data Science. Prepare different programs in Artificial Intelligence for Trainees. Design and build systems that mine massive datasets and structure/engineer it to be useable for machine learning models. Explore and suggest AI based solutions such as Convolutional Neural Networks. Apply machine learning techniques to deliver actionable insights from large-scale, multi-structured datasets. Work unsupervised with internal and external teams to respond to business requirements. End to end responsibility for model development, including data exploration, training data, feature extraction and model development, validation and scoring. DEVELOPING STATISTICAL MODELS: Apply advanced techniques such as ML, DNN, text mining, regression modelling, time-series analysis, cluster & factor analysis and segmentation to create different models for large data sets.

November 03, 2021 - CURRENT

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST, PRIMER TUBULAR INSPECTION SERVICES (PVT) LTD

My Responsibilities include Data Preprocessing, Data Analytics, Storytelling and Machine Learning of Oil & Energy.

November 03, 2021 - September 10, 2022

SENIOR DATA SCIENTIST, FAZAL MAHMOOD AND COMPANY CHARTERED ACCOUNTANTS (PVT) LTD

My Responsibilities include Data Preprocessing of Finance & Accounts Data. I also have to do Testing on General Ledger and Trial Balance using Python, Numpy, Pandas, Regular Expression, Matplotlib and Seaborn.

January, 2021 - November, 2021

ARTIFICAL INTELLIGENCE SPECIALIST, AL INTISAR (PVT) LTD

I was working there on contract based AI Project. The project was about TBML (Trade Based Money Laundering) Automation which is now implemented in Banks.

January, 2020 - CURRENT

DATA SCIENCES COORDINATOR, NED UNIVERSITY

Responsibilities include Data science course designing and training to students. Includes different modules ranging from data analysis to machine learning.

February, 2020 - CURRENT

FOUNDER & DATA SCIENCE TRAINER, TECHMAZONE

Founded TechmaZone institute specifically for Data science extensive training focusing on more practical work.

January, 2020 - December, 2020

DATA ANALYST, ICI PAKISTAN (PVT) LTD

Worked there as data analyst, extracting results from their data and maintained dashboards accordingly using Power Bi, SharePoint and core python libraries like Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib.

January, 2019 - December, 2020

DATA SCIENCE TRAINER, AMI APEX

Responsibilities include Data science course designing and training to students. Includes different modules ranging from data analysis to machine learning.

January, 2018 - December, 2020

VISTING FACULTY, APTECH COMPUTER EDUCATION

Conducted trainings and workshops on Web Designing and Development, Android mobile apps development and different programming languages.

EDUCATION

January, 2017 - December, 2020

BS COMPUTER SCIENCE, UBIT - UNIVERSITY OF KARACHI

January, 2017 - December, 2020

APTECH CERTIFIED COMPUTER PROFESSIONAL, APTECH COMPUTER EDUCATION

January, 2019 - December, 2019

APPLIED DATA SCIENCE WITH MACHINE LEARNING, AMI APEX

SOFT AND HARD SKILLS

- Data Analysis
- Statistics & Probability
- Data Visualization
- Data Preprocessing

- Machine Learning & Deep Learning
- Computer Vision
- Web Scarping & Web APIs
- Regression Analysis

- Database Management
- Data Manipulation
- Data Science Tools / Data Tools
- Data Mining
- Quantitative Analysis
- Testing Hypotheses

- Storytelling Skills
- Debugging
- Modeling
- Communication
- Problem Solving

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Python
- Numpy, Pandas
- Matplotlib, Plotly, Seaborn
- Scipy
- Beautiful Soup, Scrapy & Selenium
- Regular Expression

- PowerBI & Tableau
- XML, JSON
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- openCV, OCR
- Sciket-Learn, Keras & Tensorflow
- SQLite, MySQL, PostreSQL & SQL Server

DATA SCIENCE PROJECT

- App Profiles Analysis
- Exploring News Posts
- Exploring Car Sales Data
- Analyzing and Visualizing Earnings Based On Different Majors
- Exploring and Visualizing The Gender Gap
- Analyze Employee Exit Surveys
- Analyzing New York City (NYC) Data
- Analyzing Movie Survey
- Analyzing CIA Data (Using Databases and SQL)
- Answering Business Questions (Using Databases and SQL)
- Scrapping Website for live Data Analysis (Using Web Scraping and APIs)
- Analyzing Business
- Investigating Ratings (Using Statistics)
- Finding the Best Markets to Advertise In (Using Statistics)
- Modeling App for Lottery Addiction (Using Probabilities)
- Building a Spam Filter (Using Naive Bayes and Conditional Probabilities)
- Working on Winning Jeopardy (Using Hypothesis Testing)
- K-means clustering (Using Unsupervised Learning)
- Predicting Car Prices (Using KNN Algorithm)
- Predicting House Sale Prices (Using Calculus, Linear Algebra & Linear Regression)
- Predicting the Stock Market (Using Logistic Regression)
- Predicting Bike Rentals (Using Decision Tree and Random Forest)
- Image Classification (Using Deep Learning)
- Comprehensive Machine Learning Walkthrough Project 1.0 (Ensemble Method)
- Comprehensive Machine Learning Walkthrough Project 2.0 (Ensemble Method)
- Building Natural Language Processing (NLP) model

AWARDS

May, 2017

WEBATHON COMPETITION 2017 WINNER, APTECH COMPUTER EDUCATION

January, 2018

WEBATHON COMPETITION 2018 WINNER, APTECH COMPUTER EDUCATION